<START/>
Required input format:
- Of course you don't need the above line, but it will ignored by the processor, 
so no problem; my comments outside the tags will also be ignored...

below you first say \vc meaning pada c, but actually the lemma is in pada a; correct it by 
making another <APP> <LEM></LEM> </APP> section above the present one, or actually under the first line of the verse; similarly dātā should go with \vd in a separate <APP> <LEM></LEM> </APP> line; you will end up with three <APP> <LEM></LEM> </APP> lines for 
padas a, c and d.

You can put a title here if you want like:

<TITLE>Śivadharmottara chapter 2</TITLE>


For the automatic verse numbering put this here:
<NEWCHAPTER/>

You can (maybe should) put also this:
<ANUSTUBH/>
This performs some formatting and is also needed for correct verse numbering (mainly if you have other stanza forms...)

<TEXT> yāvadakṣarasaṃkhyānaṃ śivajñānasya pustake |</TEXT>
<TEXT> tāvadvarṣasahasrāṇi dātā śivapure vaset ||</TEXT>
    <APP>\vc <LEM>°saṃkhyānaṃ </LEM> \msALL; °santāna \msNKo77
              <LEM>varṣa°</LEM> \msNC45\msNK82\msE; kalpa° \msNCA12\msNK28\msNKo77\P
              <LEM>dātā</LEM> \msALL; hotā \msGP74</APP>
    <TR>As many letters are in the manuscript of the knowledge of Śiva,
      so many thousand years the donor will live in the town of Śiva.</TR>
    <NOTE>This is the place for the notes...</NOTE>

Below similarly make a <APP> <LEM></LEM> </APP> line for each pada
Use a \oo after the variants of a lemma if there is another lemma in the same pada:
this separates the two entries fo the same pada



vaṃśyāṃś is in pada b so go for \vb ('verse [pada] b')

    <TEXT> daśa pūrvān samuddhṛtya daśa vaṃśyāṃś ca paścimān |</TEXT>
    <TEXT> mātāpitṛdharmapatnīḥ svarge sthāpya śivaṃ vrajet ||</TEXT>
        <APP>\vc <LEM>vaṃśyāṃś  </LEM> \msNC45\msNK82\msGP74; vaṃśāś \msNKA12\msNK28\msNKo77\msE; vaśyāṃś \msGP43
                  <LEM>varṣa°</LEM> \msNC45\msNK82\msE; kalpa° \msNCA12\msNK28\msNKo77\P
                  <LEM>dātā</LEM> \msALL; hotā \msGP74</APP>
        <TR>Having rescued ten ancestors and the ten descendants,
          having brought to Heaven [his] mother, father and lawful wife, 
			he will attain Śiva.</TR>
        <NOTE>This is the place for the notes...</NOTE>

And use ';' only after the sigla of the accepted reading/lemma.
Use commas for separating the non-accepted variants. This helps the program figure out which are the sigla for the lemma:  
"; vaśyāṃś \msGP43" 
	above should read
", vaśyāṃś \msGP43" 

Also: I would perhaps use \msP instead of \P, because \P sometimes just means 'P' for the computer, so it is safer to use \msP
  
And I forgot to tell you to put this at the end
<STOP/>

This now puts some stuff in which is needed for that hovering mouse trick...

